<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ftvkyo</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on ftvkyo</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025 in review</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/2025-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/2025-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last year, I wrote &lt;a href="https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/2024-in-review">2024 in review&lt;/a>.
There are many good things about that post.
I reviewed it a few times throughout the year, curious about the changes in my mental state since then and about the goals I had set.
It has also been fun to share it with my friends and acquaintances.
And, most importantly, it presented a good opportunity for reflection at the time of writing.
So, here I am, writing a follow-up :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024 in review</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/2024-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/2024-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I considered writing a follow-up for &lt;a href="https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/my-time-and-focus-02/">My Time and Focus&lt;/a> posts, titled &amp;laquo;My Time and Focus. 2 years later&amp;raquo;.
I thought I couldn&amp;rsquo;t finish writing it in one day, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t start.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is what I am writing instead.
It will touch on some of the topics I wanted to bring up, but won&amp;rsquo;t go into as much detail.
This is a spontaneous decision, I am doing it instead of other plans.
But today is a holiday, so I am fine with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making a "Known Error" app for Tildagon</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/tildagon-known-error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/tildagon-known-error/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the end of May 2024, I went to my first &lt;a href="https://emfcamp.org">EMF Camp&lt;/a>, and I loved it.
It had many interesting things to see and cool people to meet.
I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I made new friends there, but I did get closer to members of &lt;a href="https://wiki.ehlab.uk">Edinburgh Hacklab&lt;/a> which I am also a member of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is not about EMF Camp though, it is about one of its highlights: the &lt;a href="https://tildagon.badge.emfcamp.org/">Tildagon&lt;/a> badge.
These badges are electronic devices that are meant to be extended and modified, this is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hacker">hacker&lt;/a> festival after all.
The badges could be preordered for 25£.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hovert60 keyboard devlog #2: Design</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-hovert60-02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-hovert60-02/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the &lt;a href="https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-hovert60-01/">previous post&lt;/a> on the topic, I introcuded my new project: making a personalized mechanical keyboard from scratch.
I described my criteria for the end result and showed you the components I intend to use.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is focused on the design process of the project.
The posts are sequential, but in reality they go hand-in-hand.
The design influences which components can be used.
Availability, price and properties of the components influence the design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hovert60 keyboard devlog #1: Init</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-hovert60-01/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-hovert60-01/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I have been a mild fan of mechanical and &lt;a href="https://deskthority.net/wiki/Ergonomic_keyboard">ergonomic&lt;/a> keyboards for a while now.
I have used &lt;a href="https://ergodox-ez.com/">Ergodox EZ&lt;/a>, Planck EZ &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and &lt;a href="https://drop.com/buy/preonic-mechanical-keyboard">OLKB Preonic&lt;/a>.
Additionally, my XKB configuration is somewhat interesting.&lt;/p>


&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://www.ftvkyo.me/img/post/devlog-hovert60-01/preonic.jpg"
 alt="OLKB Planck with &amp;laquo;ergonomic&amp;raquo; wristrests">&lt;figcaption>
 &lt;p>OLKB Planck with &amp;laquo;ergonomic&amp;raquo; wristrests&lt;/p>
 &lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>You see, Russian alphabet has 33 letters, while English only has 26.
This means that on the default Russian layout more keys are used for letters, and punctuation keys are different from the US layout.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website overhaul</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/website-03-overhaul/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/website-03-overhaul/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have done a major overhaul of the website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The primary focus was on styling.
I was not satisfied with the original theme (&lt;a href="https://github.com/zwbetz-gh/cayman-hugo-theme">Cayman&lt;/a>) and wanted to change it.
The problem was not in the look of the theme, but in how much tweaking I wanted to do, so it was easier to just make a new theme of my own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have also changed the way the website is built.
I used to have the website sources in a public Github repository and the deployments were done with a Github Action, to a &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> branch in the same repo.
I have moved the sources of the website to a separate repository and the deployments are set up to update &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> in the original repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Time and Focus. Part 2: But how?</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/my-time-and-focus-02/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/my-time-and-focus-02/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://www.ftvkyo.me/img/post/my-time-and-focus-02/reintroduction.svg"
 alt="An arrow with a loop in the middle, representing &amp;#34;reintroduction&amp;#34;.">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="reintroduction">Reintroduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the &lt;a href="https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/my-time-and-focus-01/">previous part&lt;/a> I have gone through some tools and approaches to self-organisation.
The main focus was on note-taking, and now it is finally time to highlight some neat parts of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have already more-or-less described the criteria that I want the note-taking system to satisfy, and why I need it, so here I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about its &lt;strong>implementation details&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Time and Focus. Part 1: But why?</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/my-time-and-focus-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/my-time-and-focus-01/</guid><description>&lt;figure>&lt;img src="https://www.ftvkyo.me/img/post/my-time-and-focus-01/fix-all-problems.svg"
 alt="Checkbox &amp;#34;Fix all problems&amp;#34;">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The purpose of this series of posts is to share some details of my journey of organizing myself.
I think this might be interesting or even useful for somebody, but I am mostly writing this to stay motivated to continue (and as writing practice).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll start by explaining the problems I&amp;rsquo;m trying to solve and why they matter.
Along the way, I might learn new things or find some insights I missed in the past.
In other words, I want to begin by describing things I already understand, and after that, I would like to continue the series by making &amp;laquo;progress updates&amp;raquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website tweaks</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/website-02-tweaks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/website-02-tweaks/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have done some minor optimization of the website in order to improve its
Lighthouse score and its performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The score should be above 90% in every category (except PWA that I don&amp;rsquo;t target)
at the moment of publishing this post. I only tested it on localhost,
but as the most significant problem was caused by Google Fonts the website
depends on, that part should be the same as in production.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parentheses programming language devlog #1: getting to LLVM IR emission</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-parentheses-01/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 21:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/devlog-parentheses-01/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="pre-intro">Pre-intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I start these series hoping to continue them along with the development of
the project this devlog is related to.
Not only the project is an excercise for me, but the devlog itself is as well.
I think about making some games in the future, and how could I make a good
game without having a devlog about it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, thanks to all the advice from different people who suggested some better
techniques of dealing with challenges I face in this project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A New Website</title><link>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/website-01-new/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 20:20:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.ftvkyo.me/post/website-01-new/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anybody here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got this thought to make my website a very long time ago. A classic
idea for a developer, right? However, I could never finish its creation.
For a long time, I had some random pages dangling on my domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always wanted to put something interesting there, and as I never truly
needed a website, I just played with different things abandoning them later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only two attempts were notable. One where I made it work, with some pages
and even some interactivity, but it all was weird, as I started trying out
some unrelated ideas. &amp;laquo;What if I use Python for boring content serving and Rust
for a quick API?&amp;raquo; (not that I needed this API). I managed to make it work,
it was running in Docker for quite a while, but it had zero useful
content and almost no value except the experience I got from it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>